<schemalist>

  <enum id="com.inform7.IDE.preferences.font-set-enum">
    <value nick="Standard" value="0" />
    <value nick="Monospace" value="1" />
    <value nick="Custom" value="2" />
  </enum>

  <enum id="com.inform7.IDE.preferences.font-size-enum">
    <value nick="Standard" value="0" />
    <value nick="Medium" value="1" />
    <value nick="Large" value="2" />
    <value nick="Huge" value="3" />
  </enum>

  <enum id="com.inform7.IDE.preferences.interpreter-enum">
    <value nick="Glulxe (default)" value="0" />
    <value nick="Git" value="1" />
  </enum>

  <schema id="com.inform7.IDE" path="/com/inform7/IDE/">
    <child name="preferences" schema="com.inform7.IDE.preferences"/>
    <child name="state" schema="com.inform7.IDE.state"/>
  </schema>

  <schema id="com.inform7.IDE.preferences" path="/com/inform7/IDE/preferences/">
    <child name="skein" schema="com.inform7.IDE.preferences.skein"/>

    <key name="author-name" type="s">
      <default>''</default>
      <summary>Preferred author's name for Inform 7 projects</summary>
      <description>The name you prefer to use for your new Inform 7 projects. If
      this field is left blank, then your long username is used instead. Note
      that you can always change the name you are writing under after you have
      created the project.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="font-set" enum="com.inform7.IDE.preferences.font-set-enum">
      <default>'Standard'</default>
      <summary>Font set to use in the Source panel</summary>
      <description>Font set to use in the Source panel. Allowed values are
      "Standard", "Monospace", and "Custom". The first two look for the default
      proportional and monospace fonts from your desktop theme, respectively,
      and the latter uses the custom font you select yourself (see
      custom-font).</description>
    </key>

    <key name="custom-font" type="s">
      <default>'Sans 11'</default>
      <summary>Custom font to use in the Source panel</summary>
      <description>Font to use in the Source panel if font-set (q.v.) is set to
      "Custom".</description>
    </key>

    <key name="font-size" enum="com.inform7.IDE.preferences.font-size-enum">
      <default>'Standard'</default>
      <summary>Font size to use in the application</summary>
      <description>Font size to use in the application. Allowed values are
      "Standard", "Medium", "Large", and "Huge". These correspond to multipliers
      of 1.0, 1.2, 1.4, and 1.8, respectively.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="style-scheme" type="s">
      <default>'inform'</default>
      <summary>Style scheme to use in the application</summary>
      <description>Name of the style scheme to use in the application. The style
      scheme defines the colors and styles of all of the different highlighting
      possibilities of the Natural Inform language.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="tab-width" type="u">
      <default>0</default>
      <summary>Tab width to use in the Source panel</summary>
      <description>Tab width, in spaces, to use in the Source panel. A value of
      0 means use the default tab width.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="elastic-tabstops-padding" type="u">
      <default>16</default>
      <range min="1" max="999"/> <!-- no obvious max -->
      <summary>Number of pixels of padding between elastic tabstops</summary>
      <description>If elastic tabstops are turned on, there will be this many
      pixels of padding inserted between the tabstops.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="syntax-highlighting" type="b">
      <default>true</default>
      <summary>Use syntax highlighting in the Source panel</summary>
      <description>Syntax highlighting will automatically color and style your
      source code to indicate what different parts do. If you  have a slow
      computer, you may see a performance benefit by turning this
      off.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="auto-indent" type="b">
      <default>true</default>
      <summary>Use auto-indenting in the Source panel</summary>
      <description>If this option is selected, Inform will track the number of
      tabs at the beginning of the last line and automatically indent the next
      line accordingly when you insert a new line by pressing
      return.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="indent-wrapped" type="b">
      <default>true</default>
      <summary>Indent wrapped lines in the Source panel</summary>
      <description>If this option is selected, Inform will indent wrapped lines
      by a half tabstop. This makes it easier to see where a line break happened
      because of a long line.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="intelligence" type="b">
      <default>true</default>
      <summary>Use intelligent symbol following in the Source panel</summary>
      <description>Inform can keep track of important items in your source files
      as you type. Enabling this option will allow it to automatically track
      sections in Natural Inform files.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="auto-number" type="b">
      <default>false</default>
      <summary>Auto-number sections as you type</summary>
      <description>If you check this option, Inform will automatically renumber
      sections when you insert a new one. It will also automatically insert a
      section number as you type: if you type "Part ", Inform will insert "2 - "
      and renumber the previous Part 2 to Part 3 and so on.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="interpreter" enum="com.inform7.IDE.preferences.interpreter-enum">
      <default>'Glulxe (default)'</default>
      <summary>Use the Git interpreter for Glulx story files</summary>
      <description>This setting determines the interpreter to use in the Game
      tab for Glulx story files: Git or Glulxe. Previous versions of Inform 7
      used Glulxe, which is still the default, but in the future Git may become
      standard.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="clean-build-files" type="b">
      <default>true</default>
      <summary>Clean build files from projects before closing</summary>
      <description>Build files are files that are generated while turning your
      story into a game file. Selecting this option will ensure that they are
      deleted when you close or save a project. These files can grow quite large
      (many times the size of your source code), so deleting them is a good idea
      if you are planning to send a project to someone else.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="clean-index-files" type="b">
      <default>false</default>
      <summary>Clean index files from projects before closing</summary>
      <description>Selecting this option will cause Inform to additionally clean
      out the project's various index files. These are generated by the Inform 7
      compiler and can be safely deleted, though they may be useful the next
      time you open the project.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="show-debug-log" type="b">
      <default>false</default>
      <summary>Show debugging log and Inform 6 intermediate code</summary>
      <description>This option places two extra tabs in the Errors panel,
      containing a debugging log and the Inform 6 intermediate code. It is
      intended only for advanced users of Inform 7. It is most useful to people
      involved with maintaining the compiler, although the Inform 6 intermediate
      code may be of interest to especially advanced extension
      authors.</description>
    </key>

  </schema>

  <schema id="com.inform7.IDE.state" path="/com/inform7/IDE/state/">

    <key name="spell-check" type="b">
      <default>true</default>
      <summary>Spell check the Source</summary>
      <description>Default setting for spell checking when opening a new
      window.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="show-toolbar" type="b">
      <default>true</default>
      <summary>Show the toolbar</summary>
      <description>Default setting for showing the toolbar when opening a new
      window.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="show-statusbar" type="b">
      <default>true</default>
      <summary>Show the status bar</summary>
      <description>Default setting for showing the status bar when opening a new
      window.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="show-notepad" type="b">
      <default>false</default>
      <summary>Show the notepad</summary>
      <description>Default setting for showing the notepad when opening a new
      window.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="elastic-tabstops" type="b">
      <default>false</default>
      <summary>Use elastic tabstops</summary>
      <description>Default setting for using elastic tabstops when opening a new
      window.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="app-window-size" type="(ii)">
      <default>(1000, 800)</default>
      <summary>Default size of application window</summary>
      <description>Width and height, in pixels, for newly-created application
      windows.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="divider-position" type="i">
      <default>500</default>
      <range min="0" max="9999"/> <!--no obvious max-->
      <summary>Position of divider between the two pages</summary>
      <description>Position of the divider between the two halves of the
      application window, in pixels, for newly-created application
      windows.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="ext-window-size" type="(ii)">
      <default>(500, 650)</default>
      <summary>Default size of extension window</summary>
      <description>Width and height, in pixels, for newly-created extension
      windows.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="notepad-position" type="(ii)">
      <default>(0, 0)</default>
      <summary>Default position of notepad window</summary>
      <description>Position, in pixels, at which the notepad window will be
      placed when it is shown.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="notepad-size" type="(ii)">
      <default>(300, 300)</default>
      <summary>Default size of notepad window</summary>
      <description>Width and height, in pixels, of the notepad
      window.</description>
    </key>

  </schema>

  <schema id="com.inform7.IDE.preferences.skein"
    path="/com/inform7/IDE/preferences/skein/">

    <key name="horizontal-spacing" type="d">
      <default>40</default>
      <range min="0" max="100"/>
      <summary>Horizontal spacing between Skein branches</summary>
      <description>Approximate horizontal spacing, in pixels, between branches
      in the Skein tab.</description>
    </key>

    <key name="vertical-spacing" type="d">
      <default>75</default>
      <range min="0" max="200"/>
      <summary>Vertical spacing between Skein branches</summary>
      <description>Approximate vertical spacing, in pixels, between branches in
      the Skein tab.</description>
    </key>

  </schema>

</schemalist>
