<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.inform7.IDE</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0 AND Artistic-2.0</project_license>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0" />
  <name>Inform</name>
  <summary>Write interactive fiction</summary>
  <keywords>
    <keyword translate="no">IDE</keyword>
    <keyword>interactive fiction</keyword>
    <keyword translate="no">inform</keyword>
    <keyword translate="no">GNOME</keyword>
    <keyword translate="no">GTK</keyword>
    <keyword>development</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <description>
    <p>
      Official development environment for Inform, a programming language for
      creating interactive fiction, using natural language syntax.
      Using natural language and drawing on ideas from linguistics and from
      literate programming, Inform is widely used as a medium for literary
      writing, as a prototyping tool in the games industry, and in education, both
      at school and university level (where Inform is often assigned material for
      courses on digital narrative).
    </p>
    <p>
      Inform is a design system for interactive fiction based on natural
      language, a new medium of writing which came out of the "text adventure"
      games of the 1980s.
      It has been used by many leading writers of IF over the last twenty
      years, for projects ranging from historical reconstructions, through
      games, to art pieces, which have won numerous awards and competitions.
    </p>
    <p>
      Inform's educational users span a uniquely wide age range, from primary
      schools to graduate computer science classes.
      Although Inform has also been used for commercial commissions, in
      architecture, in the games industry and in advertising (most recently
      for a major 2014 product launch), its primary aim is to help and to
      encourage individual writers to express themselves in a new medium.
      In a single evening with Inform, it's possible to write a vignette and
      publish it as an interactive website, playable on any browser.
    </p>
    <p>
      The Inform project was created by Graham Nelson in 1993 and first came to
      the Macintosh Programmer's Workshop in 1995, and is now available as an app.
      It combines the core Inform software with full documentation, including two
      books and nearly 500 fully working examples. Connecting to the Inform website,
      it can automatically download and update extensions from a fully curated Public
      Library used by the world-wide Inform community. The app offers richly detailed
      indexing of projects and scales from tiny fictions like "Kate is a woman in the
      Research Lab" right up to enormous imaginary worlds whose source text runs to
      over 3 million words. Features for automated testing, packaging and releasing
      round out a fully-featured development environment for IF.
    </p>
    <p>
      Inform is free, with no strings attached. What you make with it is yours, to
      publish on your website, sell, or give to your friends. There's a vibrant community
      of users who welcome newcomers (and the app will help you find a high-traffic forum
      for discussions). Lastly, Inform is continuously maintained and developed. All bug
      reports are examined and acted on (and the app will show you how to post them).
    </p>
    <p>
      The source code behind the Inform 7 design system itself is linked here:
      https://github.com/ganelson/inform/
    </p>
    <p>
      The source code behind this IDE is linked here:
      https://github.com/ptomato/inform7-ide/
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.inform7.IDE.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ptomato/inform7-ide/main/pixmaps/screenshots/source.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ptomato/inform7-ide/main/pixmaps/screenshots/skein.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ptomato/inform7-ide/main/pixmaps/screenshots/welcome.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://ganelson.github.io/inform-website/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://ganelson.github.io/inform-website/bugs/</url>
  <url type="help">https://ganelson.github.io/inform-website/doc/</url>
  <url type="donation">https://ganelson.github.io/inform-website/donate/</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/ptomato/inform7-ide/</url>
  <url type="contribute">https://github.com/ganelson/inform/</url>
  <releases>
    <release version="2.0.0" date="2022-09-03">
      <description>
        <p>
          Long-awaited 2.0.0 release, corresponding to Inform 10.1.2.
        </p>
        <p>
          Inform 10.1.2 was released on August 31st 2022, with changes to the build manager
          to fix sandboxing issues on Linux that prevented the building and publishing of a
          Linux build of Inform 10.1.1, as well as 10 other bug fixes.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
